Let's return to this equation,
我们回到这个等式
which we used to show how to do inference by enumeration.
这个等式曾用来表示如何通过列举法进行推理
In this equation we join up the whole joint distribution
在这个等式中 我们连接了整个联合分布
before we sum out over the hidden variables.
然后对隐变量进行求和
That's slow, because we end up repeating a lot of work.
因为我们最后要重复大量工作 所以这非常慢
Now we're going to show a new technique called
我们要展示一种新技巧
variable elimination which in many networks operates much faster.
叫做变量消元算法 在许多网络中可以运算更快
It's still a difficult computation and
在一般情况中 利用贝叶斯网络
a bit hard computation to do inference over Bayes nets in general.
进行推理 仍然是很难的计算
Variable elimination works faster than inference by enumeration
大多数实际情况下 变量消元比列举法
in most practical cases.
推理速度更快
It requires an algebra for manipulating factors, which are just names for
这种方法需要操作因子的代数 即来自
multidimensional arrays that come out of these probabilistic terms.
这些概率项的多维数组名称
We'll use another example to show how variable elimination works.
我们使用另一个例子展现变量消元的原理
We'll start off with a network that has three boolean variables.
我们首先从包含三个布尔变量的网络开始
R indicates whether or not it's raining.
R 表示有没有下雨
T indicates whether or not there's traffic.
T 表示有没有堵车
And T is dependent on whether it's raining.
T 依赖于有没有下雨 R
And finally L indicates whether or not I'll be late for my next appointment and
最后 L 表示我接下来的约会有没有迟到
that depends on whether or not there's traffic.
这取决于有没有堵车
Now,we'll put up the conditional probability tables for
现在我们贴出这三个变量的
each of these three variables.
条件变量表格
And then we can use inference to figure out answer to questions like
我们可以使用推理 计算出
am I going to be late?
我是否迟到这类问题的答案吗？
And we know by definition that we could do that through enumeration
根据定义我们知道 可以通过列举法
by going through all the possible values for r and t, and
找出 R 和 T 所有可能的值
summing up the product of these three nodes.
然后对这三个节点的乘积进行求和 得出答案
Now in a simple network like this, straight enumeration would work fine.
在这个简单的网络中 清晰条理的列举法会很有效
But in a more complex network, what variable elimination does is give us
但是在更加复杂的网络中 变量消元可以让我们
a way to combine together parts of the network into smaller parts, and
把网络组合起来的各部分 拆分成更小的部分
then enumerate over those smaller parts and then continue combining them.
然后列举这些更小的部分 然后继续组合
So we start with a big network, we eliminate some of the variables,
那么我们处理较大网络 消除一些变量
we compute by marginalizing out and then we have a smaller network to deal with.
我们通过排除一些内容进行计算 然后处理更小的网络
And we'll show you how those two steps work.
我们会展现如何实现这两步
The first operation in variable elimination is called joining factors.
变量消元第一步叫做连接因子
A factor again is one of these tables, it's a multi dimensional matrix.
因子是这些表格中的一个 是多维矩阵
And what we do is choose two of the factors, two or
我们要选择两个或
more of the factors, in this case we'll choose these two.
多个因子 在这个例子中我们选择两个
And we'll combine them together to form a new factor which represents
我们把它们组合起来 形成一个新因子
the joint probability of all the variables in that factor.
代表这个因子中所有变量的联合概率
In this case, R and T.
在这个例子中是 R 和 T
Now we'll draw that table.
现在我们绘制表格
In each case, we just look up in the corresponding table,
在每个情况中 我们只观察对应的表格
figure out the numbers, and multiply them together.
计算数字 然后相乘
For example, in this row, we have a +r and a +t.
例如在这一行中 我们有 +r 和 +t
So the +r is 0.1 and the entry for +r and +t is 0.8, so
所以 P(+r) 是 0.1 P(+t|+r) 是 0.8
multiply them together and you get 0.08.
所以两者相乘得到 0.08
Go all the way down for example in the last row we have a -r and
继续看最后一行 我们有 -r 和 -t
a -t, -r is 0.9.
P(-r) 是 0.9
The entry for -r and -t is also 0.9.
P(-t|-r) 也是 0.9
Multiply those together and you get 0.81.
两者相乘得到 0.81
So what have we done?
那么我们完成了什么？
We used the operation of joining factors of these two factors giving us a new
我们使用组合因子操作 把两个因子结合起来
factor which is part of the existing network.
得到一个新因子 作为已有网络的一部分
Now we want to apply a second operation called elimination, also called
现在我们要应用第二步操作 叫做消元
summing out or marginalization, to take this table and reduce it.
也叫做排除法 得到这个表格然后排除
Right now the tables we have look like this.
刚才我们得到这样的表格
We can sum, out or marginalize,
我们可以对变量 r 求和或排除
over the variable r to give us a table that just operates on t.
得到只对 t 操作的表格
So the question is to fill in this table for P(T).
所以问题是填写 P(T) 表格
There will be two entries in this table, the +t entry formed by summing out
这个表格包括两列 通过消除
all the entries here for all values of r for which t is positive.
这里 t为正时所有 r 的值 得到 +t 这一项
And the -t entry formed the same way, by looking in this table and
以同样的方式形成 -t 这一项 通过观察这个表格
summing up all the rows, over all values of r where T is negative.
对所有行进行求和 除以 t 为负时所有值
Put your answers in these boxes.
在这些空格中填写你的答案
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[背景音]